Davide Vernizzi

Curriculum Vitæ

Via Belfiore, 42 10125, Torino, Italy \$\mathref{s}\mathre{s}\mathre{s} 329 24 73 484

 $\bowtie davide.vernizzi@gmail.com$

I am currently working as a software engineer at Ennova SrI, which was awarded with the prize of Italian Startup of Year 2014.

I develop web applications, backends, and APIs for mobile applications, which are mainly used by telecommunication companies and energy providers, such as Telecom Italia, Vodafone, Enel, and Iren Energia.

While working at Ennova, I have been in charge of integrating clients' databases, I developed web services used by clients' IVR, and I coordinated the efforts of Ennova's developers in order to develop various mobile apps. Moreover, I personally developed some of the most critical server side building blocks in many projects, and I have helped to design Ennova's cloud computing architecture.

Before working on web and mobile applications, I obtained a Ph.D in security of computer systems. In this context, I have participated in the European research project Open_TC, aimed at creating an open-source framework for Trusted Computing. Following this, I worked on security of cloud computing, contributing to the research project TClouds, whose goal was to create a resilient and privacy-friendly cloud computing platform.

While holding my positions, both in university and in industry, I have always been involved into the training of students or new employees.

Education

15 April 2010 Ph.D. in Computer Science, Politecnico di Torino.

Thesis: On Trusted and Privacy-Friendly Network Communications.

Advisor: prof. Antonio Lioy.

5 May 2006 M.Sc. in Computer Engineering, Politecnico di Torino.

Thesis: Self-adaptive parallel algorithms for computer vision applications. This thesis was written in collaboration with the École Nationale Supérieure d'Informatique et des Mathématiques Appliquées de Grenoble (ENSIMAG).

Advisors: prof. Bartrolomeo Montrucchio (POLITO), prof. Jean-Louis Roch (ENSIMAG).

11 July 2005 **Diplôme d'Ingénieur (equivalent to M.Sc. in Computer Engineering)**, École Nationale Supérieure d'Informatique et des Mathématiques Appliquées de Grenoble (ENSIMAG).

Thesis: Self-adaptive parallel algorithms for computer vision applications.

Advisor: prof. Jean-Louis Roch (ENSIMAG).

12 Sept. 2003 B.Sc. in Computer Engineering, Politecnico di Torino.

Work experience

since 2011 Developer, Ennova s.r.l, http://www.ennova.it/.

Development of web and mobile applications for customer care. Integration and development of enterprise services on behalf of telephone companies and energy providers.

2010 – 2011 Postdoctoral researcher, Politecnico di Torino, Dip. di Automatica e Informatica. Following the Ph.D I continued my research activity at Politecnico di Torino, focusing on Cloud Computing.

2006 – 2010 Research activity, Politecnico di Torino, Dip. di Automatica e Informatica.

Research activity at Politecnico di Torino on security of computer systems and network. The research activities were mainly focused to *Trusted Computing* and its application to network of computers, with a particular attention to privacy.

2009-2010 Consultant, SmartRM S.r.l., http://www.smartrm.com, Torino.

> Consulting activity for SmartRM, a company specialized in developing encryption software that allows users to easily protect and share digital content. I helped SmartRM to integrate Trusted Computing principles to content protection.

2005 **Internship**, *ID-IMAG*, http://bit.ly/id-imag, Grenoble, Francia.

Study and development of parallel algorithms used for computer vision.

2003. 2004 **Internship**, *Dynamic Fun S.r.l.*, http://www.dynamicfun.com/, Torino. Study and development of algorithms for face detection

Research projects

2010-2011 TClouds (Trustworthy Clouds), www.tclouds-project.eu.

> TClouds is EU-funded research project. Its main goal is to develop an advanced cloud infrastructure that can deliver computing and storage that achieves a new level of security, privacy, and resilience.

Main partners: IBM, Philips, University of Oxford.

STORK (Secure Identity Across Borders Linked), www.eid-stork.eu. 2010-2011

> STORK project was funded by the European Commission as part of its Competitiveness and Innovation Programme. Its aim is to establish a European electronic ID Interoperability Platform that will allow citizens to use their national eID for authenticating and accessing electronic services across Europe.

Main partners: 14 EU Member States.

2009-2010 Trusted Platform Agent, http://goo.gl/mLodg4.

C library (Linux, Windows) for application exploiting Trusted Computing and TPM.

2007-2009 Open_TC (Open Trusted Computing), http://goo.gl/IDlKeB.

> Development of a framework for Trusted Computing based on open source software. Main partners: IBM, HP, Infineon, AMD.

Skills

Linux, Mac OS X, Windows OS

Programming C, Java, Python

MySQL, UML, Vim, LATEX, Office Altro

PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS Web

Languages and other information

Native language: Italian. Fluent in English and French. Languages

Teaching at Politecnico di Torino as teacher assistant and teaching to private com-**Teaching**

panies as teacher.